<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mila Frerichs</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mila Frerichs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 11:11:32 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Work Journal: March 31st</title>
      <link>/journal/work-journal-march-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 11:11:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/journal/work-journal-march-31/</guid>
      <description>I want to share more what I do every day, so I&amp;rsquo;m starting this (weekly) journal after inspiration from Adam Wathan. Love what the guy is doing so I will do something similar.
Waiting list for my upcoming online-course This week started off very well with the public launch of the waiting list for my upcoming Online Workshop about &amp;ldquo;Geospatial Data Visualization with d3&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m excited about the launch of the waiting list for my first product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cv/</guid>
      <description>Curriculum Vitae Professionel Civic Vision UGsince August 2014Owner, Developer
 Zweitag GmbHFeb 2013 - July 2014Software Developer (student trainee), Ruby on Rails, Javascript
 Avency GmbHFeb 2009 - Jan 2013Frontend Developer (student trainee), Javascript
 Institute for GeoinformaticsMarch 2008 - Feb 2009student trainee
 Education Westfälische Wilhems-Universität Münster2005 - 2015program: Geoinformatics
 Nonprofit commitment Code for Münster / Code for GermanyFeb 2014 - Nov 2015Lab Lead
 Münster Cardianls e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/me/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Mila Frerichs. I love to help advocacy groups and non-profits make cities and the world a better place. That&amp;rsquo;s why I love what I do and would not exchange it for a regular job.
I use my software development skills to do good and help others. I am fortunate that I can use my passion to make a living.
I love what I do and if I would not have founded my own company Civic Vision in 2014, I would volunteer my time to do good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/now/</guid>
      <description> Last updated: 25.03.2019
Right now I’m in Berlin with my wife and our dog Ruby. I’m currently working with streetmix to improve their testing.
I’m available for work in May.
Next conferences I attend/talk  S-H-O-W, April, Utrecht, NL FOSS4G NA, April 2019, San Diego, USA GoodTechFest, May 2019, Chicago, USA  Next family trips  None is planned right now Will be more short term weekend trips probably  What I will be working on  Improve your organizations outreach by creating data visualizations to increase engagement Help your organization to tell stories with data Help organizations find Open Data for their projects and reports Improve or create data pipelines for organizations Help grow your civic tech prototype to a more mature application  What I will not be working on  Projects without an social impact Random react/angular projects  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/legal/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/legal/privacy/</guid>
      <description>Datenschutzerklärung: Datenschutz
Die Nutzung unserer Webseite ist in der Regel ohne Angabe personenbezogener Daten möglich. Soweit auf unseren Seiten personenbezogene Daten (beispielsweise Name, Anschrift oder eMail-Adressen) erhoben werden, erfolgt dies, soweit möglich, stets auf freiwilliger Basis. Diese Daten werden ohne Ihre ausdrückliche Zustimmung nicht an Dritte weitergegeben.
Wir weisen darauf hin, dass die Datenübertragung im Internet (z.B. bei der Kommunikation per E-Mail) Sicherheitslücken aufweisen kann. Ein lückenloser Schutz der Daten vor dem Zugriff durch Dritte ist nicht möglich.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/talks-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks-workshops/</guid>
      <description> Talks I like give talks and go to conferences.
My upcoming talks Let&amp;#39;s talk about maps Good Tech Fest, 2019  My previous talks Fast and cost effective geospatial data analysis pipeline with AWS (Lambda) FOSS4G Oceania, 2018  Mapping with d3 Good Tech Fest, 2018  Fail fast and iterate quickly Good Tech Fest, 2018  Fail fast and iterate quickly Good Tech Fest, 2018  Workshops My upcoming workshops Geospatial data visualizations with d3 FOSS4G NA, 2019  My previous workshops Geospatial data visualizations with d3 FOSS4G Oceania, 2018  Mapping with d3 FOSS4G, 2017  Mapping in d3 FOSSGIS, 2014  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Themes</title>
      <link>/themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/themes/</guid>
      <description>Instead of goals I adapted an approach by Brian Casel using themes.
I think this is more aligned with my thinking and lifestyle.Here are my themes as of February 2019.
Travel to at least two new cities/regions I want to explore more of the world.
Last year I managed to visit 4 continents. Only one is left: Antartica
This can be challenging but I want to make it someday.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>