<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mila Frerichs, Data Visualization consultant for social good</title>
    <link>http://milafrerichs.de/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mila Frerichs, Data Visualization consultant for social good</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://milafrerichs.de/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Notes</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/newsletter/2019-09-01-weekly-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/newsletter/2019-09-01-weekly-notes/</guid>
      <description>Geospatial Development FOSS4G (UK) The global FOSS4G conference ended last Friday and my twitter feed was full of it. Very interesting things, need to watch a few of those videos. I&amp;rsquo;m sad that I missed the global version of the conference this year. But I attended the North American version earlier this year, will attend the UK version later this month and likely head down to New Zealand for the Oceania version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Notes</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/newsletter/weekly-notes-2019-08-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/newsletter/weekly-notes-2019-08-25/</guid>
      <description>Geospatial Development Tool Have you checked out: http://projectionwizard.org yet?
It is a nice tool to select a good projection for the area of interest.
And take a look at this tweet ;)
https://twitter.com/BojanSavric/status/1162788720686145536
Mercator Another great look into the real size of Mercator. I&amp;rsquo;m still amazed that so many people on the web default to Mercator projections for their projects.
Here is another interactive version: https://engaging-data.com/country-sizes-mercator/
Precision and Size in GeoJSON  It&amp;rsquo;s wild how many GeoJSON files are in use with a coordinate precision of 10 or higher — I&amp;rsquo;ve seen file sizes cut in half just by hacking it down to 6 (RFC 7946 recommendation) + removing duplicate coords with zero change in visual correctness</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Notes</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/newsletter/weekly-notes-2019-08-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/newsletter/weekly-notes-2019-08-11/</guid>
      <description>I had a very busy two weeks but found some very interesting pieces the last week. I especially like the Heat Vulnerability Map from Vienna. And all over the place you see that Earth Observation (satellite) data is used more and more in analysis and data visualization. I love this trend and I love pocking not satellite data myself.
Geospatial Development Stop Using Zip Codes for Geospatial Analysis Great article by Carto explaining where Zip codes originate, why they&amp;rsquo;re not useful for geospatial analysis and what you should use instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Notes</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/newsletter/weekly-notes-2019-07-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/newsletter/weekly-notes-2019-07-28/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to this new edition of “Weekly Notes”, a weekly newsletter about Maps, Data Visualization, Civic Tech, and Open Data.
You can find previous issues here.
Geospatial Development Building Footprint Comparison 
Fascinating comparison of building footprints from Microsoft and OpenStreetMap.
I recently used the Microsoft building footprint for my Zoning analysis in San Diego. When I looked for building data I found that the Microsoft dataset was more complete than the Open Street Map data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Notes</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/newsletter/2019-07-21-weekly-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/newsletter/2019-07-21-weekly-notes/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to this new edition of &amp;ldquo;Weekly Notes&amp;rdquo;, a weekly newsletter about Maps, Data Visualization, Civic Tech and Open Data.
You can find previsous issues here
There are a lot of great maps and projects in this newsletter. Enjoy!
Geospatial Development Green Space is Good for Mental Health 
Thirty years of @NASA_Landsat data helped scientists complete the largest epidemiological study of its kind
 In a sweeping nationwide study, researchers from Denmark’s University of Aarhus found that childhood exposure to green space—parks, forests, rural lands, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Notes</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/newsletter/2019-07-14-weekly-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/newsletter/2019-07-14-weekly-notes/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to this new edition of my newsletter. I hope you all had a great week. I certainly had one.
Tools &amp;amp; Frameworks for Mapping Data After a discussion on twitter and a question I saw in a facebook group about what Tools are out there to create maps, I thought I create a list of all the tools and Frameworks I could find.
I created a new airtable and integrated it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Notes</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/newsletter/2019-07-06-weekly-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/newsletter/2019-07-06-weekly-notes/</guid>
      <description>I love that e-scooters have finally arrived in Berlin. I already used them to get around and shorten my trips. This weekend we had some close friends over, and we used the scooters to show them the city from a different perspective. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely a fun and great way to get around. Although my last work week did not feel that productive, I published two new content items last week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single family homes in San Diego</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/sandiego-zoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/sandiego-zoning/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by this article from the New York Times I wanted to create the same map for San Diego. Since the article did not include San Diego, I thought I can do it.
Residential land zone for detached single-family &amp;nbsp; other housing

As you can see, there are more single-family zones, than other residential areas. I expected that, but there is a lot of space that is not just residential zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Notes</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/newsletter/2019-07-01-weekly-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/newsletter/2019-07-01-weekly-notes/</guid>
      <description>How was your week? Mine was tumultuous. I got my Open Water Diver license, and I look forward to exploring the underwater world. But other than that a lot of stuff was going on.
What fun have you done the last week? Hit reply and share it with me.
Geospatial Development Geospatial Data Visualization with d3 Over the last couple of months, I&amp;rsquo;m preparing an online video course on creating maps with d3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Notes</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/newsletter/2019-06-18-weekly-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/newsletter/2019-06-18-weekly-notes/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend I had another session in the pool on my way of getting the Open Water Diver certificate. This is really fun and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward exploring the Oceans.
On the weekend I wanted to create something small. I wanted to create something that I might want to use for my workshops. After trying out if it would work as I would expected and it did, I started looking into javascript frameworks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VizRisk Challenge: Audience</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/vizrisk-challenge-audience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/vizrisk-challenge-audience/</guid>
      <description>When I prepare a conference talk or a workshop, I am tailoring my talk or workshop to the expected audience. For example, I will add details about the country or city the conference is in. Adding pictures of the town, or in case of my workshops use data from that city to use as examples or exercises for the participants. Thinking about who is in the audience helps them to relate more to my talk/workshop and hopefully pay closer attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Notes</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/newsletter/2019-06-09-weekly-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/newsletter/2019-06-09-weekly-notes/</guid>
      <description>Hope you had a great week. I certainly had an entertaining week. A lot of stuff has happened.
What&amp;rsquo;s new with me
I started my diving lessons to get my Open Water Diver certificate, so I can dive with my wife on our next family vacation. That should be fun. What fun vacation are you planning next? Just reply and let me know. I&amp;rsquo;m curious, especially if you plan a diving trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Makeover Monday: How Americans Sleep</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/makeover-monday-how-americans-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/makeover-monday-how-americans-sleep/</guid>
      <description>Practicing your skills is essential in every aspect of your life, primarily when you work for yourself. When I coach my softball team, I always work on the basics. We hit a lot, and we field a lot. The same is true for my work, and since I have the fortune to work for myself and make my own schedule, I always like to practice my skills.
One goal for me for this year is to share more stuff openly and not just work on my skills in private.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VizRisk Challenge Entry</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/vizrisk-challenge-entry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/vizrisk-challenge-entry/</guid>
      <description>I love playing Softball and I‘m playing for more than 10 years now, it is a great team sport and I love the mix of action, team play and personal challenge getting up 1 vs. 1 against the pitcher. I used to coach the women&amp;rsquo;s team of the town that I studied in and was asked again to coach my team here in Berlin. I love coaching a team sport, strategizing how to approach the game and most important see players improve over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOT Data Communications and Visualization Specialist -Tanzania Application</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/hot-ramani-huria/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 16:38:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/hot-ramani-huria/</guid>
      <description>Habari HOT Team,
my Name is Mila and I help civic advocacy groups and nonprofits improve the life of citizens with the help of Open Data. I use the power of public open data and open source to build tools and visualization for civic advocacy groups and non-profits to increase transparency and accountability.
I&amp;rsquo;m applying for the Data Communications and Visualization Specialist contract.
Motivation I would love to help by using my skills to communicate the success of the Ramani Huria project to the worldbank and the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work Journal: March 31st</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/journal/work-journal-march-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 11:11:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/journal/work-journal-march-31/</guid>
      <description>I want to share more what I do every day, so I&amp;rsquo;m starting this (weekly) journal after inspiration from Adam Wathan. Love what the guy is doing so I will do something similar.
Waiting list for my upcoming online-course This week started off very well with the public launch of the waiting list for my upcoming Online Workshop about &amp;ldquo;Geospatial Data Visualization with d3&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m excited about the launch of the waiting list for my first product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five podcasts that changed how I run my business</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/2016-08-02-five-podcastss/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/2016-08-02-five-podcastss/</guid>
      <description>I listen to podcasts for a while now. I started with technical podcasts like Giant Robots Smashing Into Other Giant Robots, Ruby Rogues, Core Intuition and more. I think I have an easier time listening to something than to read a blog post. I can listen to them while walking my dog, riding my bike to college back in the days or taking the train.
Since starting my own business in 2014, I listen to more and more business and freelance related podcasts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two-year anniversary</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/2016-08-01-two-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/2016-08-01-two-years/</guid>
      <description>Wow, I can’t believe it! It’s been two years already. I did it! :)
Today I’m in business for two years with my company Civic Vision. I founded the company on Aug. 2014 and am happy to report that we’re still operating and growing every year.
Our revenue grew every year and our profit as well.
I had the opportunity to work with awesome companies and organizations such as Code for America, Open Knowledge Foundation Germany, Worldbank, 18f, Terranodo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcasts I listen to regularly</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/2016-07-28-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/2016-07-28-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>I listen to podcast for a while now. I started with technical podcast like giant robots smashing into other giant robots, ruby rogues, nsbrief, etc. I love listen to podcasts even about technical stuff. I think I have an easier time listening to something than to read a blogpost. I can listen to them while walking my dog, riding my bike to college back in the days or taking the train.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inbox Zero</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/2016-07-27-inbox-zero/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/2016-07-27-inbox-zero/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m happy to be able to say: I&amp;rsquo;m back at Inbox Zero
After my last trip staying at a friends place for a week, my emails started to pile up, and my filters were not any good anymore.
So I used the last two days to clean up my inbox and add more and better filters to my inboxes.
I started with my personal account because it&amp;rsquo;s easier to clean up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help families in need: MapSwipe</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/2016-07-26-mapswipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/2016-07-26-mapswipe/</guid>
      <description>A new app launched a little more than a week ago called MapSwipe. And it is great; I try to use it every day.
You help families with mapping certain areas of the world. But it is mapping you can do without a geospatial background.
What’s the purpose  With every swipe and tap, you help put families on the map
 That’s how they describe their app. And it is that simple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress Update: Civic Tech Project</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/2016-07-25-drinking-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/2016-07-25-drinking-water/</guid>
      <description>Last week I decided I should do something with the newly released Open Data Portal of the City of San Diego. And I thought about Data Sets where I could reuse/redeploy apps from other cities. There are 44 datasets in the current portal, and I wanted to use something that could be done relatively quickly but still would be an improvement.
Finding the right dataset After looking through several datasets and trying to find apps that I could easily reuse and redeploy I found the „Monitoring of select chemical parameters in drinking water“ dataset and I remembered an app from Code for Heilbronn, Germany about drinking water quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I keep myself healthy and inspired while working for myself</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/2016-07-21-activities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/2016-07-21-activities/</guid>
      <description>Working for yourself can get lonely and monotone. Here are a few things I do to stay active and inspired.
Activities I love doing sports. I’m a very active and sport-hungry person. And I love team-sports. I play Softball for almost ten years now, and I love going to tournaments, compete and have fun with friends. I met my wife through Softball, and I’m very grateful for that. But even walking my dog is an activity I enjoy most of the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>See you at these conferences!</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/2016-07-20-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/2016-07-20-conferences/</guid>
      <description>I went to just a few conferences this year just yet but plan on going to a few more. Conferences are a good way to connect with people, learn more about your craft or other people&amp;rsquo;s business and get in the mindset of learning and speaking/socializing.
Brennan Dunn recently tweeted something which struck a nerve with me, and I regretted not going to DYFC in Sweden this year. But I will go to more conferences next year and a few more business conferences as well, and DYFC 2017 is already on my calendar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three new habits to get better at writing</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/2016-07-19-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/2016-07-19-habits/</guid>
      <description>I want to start a few habits and it’s tough to find the right ones to start and to maintain.
Getting into habits is all about consistency and trying to find the balance of too little or too much. But I think publicly committing to something is a good first step to getting really into habits.
I tried for the last months to get into reading and writing habit. And I must admit both are not doing great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nokogiri Search Helper</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/2014-01-31-nokogiri-helper/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/2014-01-31-nokogiri-helper/</guid>
      <description>I recently used Scraperwiki to scrape some data off a couple of sites.
During the development process (which I will describe in a coming post) I encountered some repetitive code/task. I then refactored the code and wrote a small class which I then would use for every site.
Most often you want the first text of the matching selector and the attr of the first element matching.
You can find the class here: {% gist 8491837%}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/cv/</guid>
      <description>Curriculum Vitae Professionel Civic Vision UGsince August 2014Owner, Developer
 Zweitag GmbHFeb 2013 - July 2014Software Developer (student trainee), Ruby on Rails, Javascript
 Avency GmbHFeb 2009 - Jan 2013Frontend Developer (student trainee), Javascript
 Institute for GeoinformaticsMarch 2008 - Feb 2009student trainee
 Education Westfälische Wilhems-Universität Münster2005 - 2015program: Geoinformatics
 Nonprofit commitment Code for Münster / Code for GermanyFeb 2014 - Nov 2015Lab Lead
 Münster Cardianls e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSS4G UK Review</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/foss4g-uk-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/articles/foss4g-uk-review/</guid>
      <description>I had a great time at FOSS4G UK last week. I was not feeling well the week before so it was a good change of pace for me. Get out and enjoy a different city. It always is sad to leave my small family (wife and dog) but I love traveling around the world.
I was looking forward to Edinburgh, I heard so many goods things about the city and Scotland in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/me/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Mila Frerichs. I love to help advocacy groups and non-profits make cities and the world a better place. That&amp;rsquo;s why I love what I do and would not exchange it for a regular job.
I use my software development skills to do good and help others. I am fortunate that I can use my passion to make a living.
I love what I do and if I would not have founded my own company Civic Vision in 2014, I would volunteer my time to do good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/now/</guid>
      <description> Last updated: 12.07.2019
Right now I’m in Berlin with my wife and our dog Ruby. I’m currently working with streetmix to improve their testing.
I’m available for work in September.
Next conferences I attend/talk  FOSS4G UK, 19-20 September 2019, Edinburgh, UK NACIS 2019, 17.-18.October 2019, Tacoma, USA  Next family trips  None is planned right now Will be more short term weekend trips probably  What I will be working on  Improve your organizations outreach by creating data visualizations to increase engagement Help your organization to tell stories with data Help organizations find Open Data for their projects and reports Improve or create data pipelines for organizations Help grow your civic tech prototype to a more mature application  What I will not be working on  Projects without an social impact Random Javascript/react/angular projects  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/legal/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/legal/privacy/</guid>
      <description>Datenschutzerklärung: Datenschutz
Die Nutzung unserer Webseite ist in der Regel ohne Angabe personenbezogener Daten möglich. Soweit auf unseren Seiten personenbezogene Daten (beispielsweise Name, Anschrift oder eMail-Adressen) erhoben werden, erfolgt dies, soweit möglich, stets auf freiwilliger Basis. Diese Daten werden ohne Ihre ausdrückliche Zustimmung nicht an Dritte weitergegeben.
Wir weisen darauf hin, dass die Datenübertragung im Internet (z.B. bei der Kommunikation per E-Mail) Sicherheitslücken aufweisen kann. Ein lückenloser Schutz der Daten vor dem Zugriff durch Dritte ist nicht möglich.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks/Workshops</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/talks-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/talks-workshops/</guid>
      <description> Talks I like giving talks and go to conferences.
My upcoming talks Distraction-free (online) maps NACIS, 2019  My previous talks Rapid and repeatable geospatial analysis with python and node using notebooks FOSS4G UK, 2019  Let&amp;#39;s talk about maps Good Tech Fest, 2019  Rapid and repeatable geospatial analysis with python and node using notebooks FOSS4G NA, 2019  Fast and cost effective geospatial data analysis pipeline with AWS (Lambda) FOSS4G Oceania, 2018  Mapping with d3 Good Tech Fest, 2018  Fail fast and iterate quickly Good Tech Fest, 2018  Fail fast and iterate quickly Good Tech Fest, 2018  Workshops My upcoming workshops Geospatial data visualizations with d3 NACIS, 2019  My previous workshops Geospatial data visualizations with d3 FOSS4G UK, 2019  Geospatial data visualizations with d3 FOSS4G NA, 2019  Geospatial data visualizations with d3 FOSS4G Oceania, 2018  Mapping with d3 FOSS4G, 2017  Mapping in d3 FOSSGIS, 2014  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Themes</title>
      <link>http://milafrerichs.de/themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://milafrerichs.de/themes/</guid>
      <description>Instead of goals I adapted an approach by Brian Casel using themes.
I think this is more aligned with my thinking and lifestyle.Here are my themes as of February 2019.
Travel to at least two new cities/regions I want to explore more of the world.
Last year I managed to visit 4 continents. Only one is left: Antartica
This can be challenging but I want to make it someday.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>