<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microposts on Mila Frerichs, Data Visualization consultant for social good</title>
    <link>/microposts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microposts on Mila Frerichs, Data Visualization consultant for social good</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 15:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/microposts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking breaks</title>
      <link>/microposts/taking-breaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/microposts/taking-breaks/</guid>
      <description>I (try to) use the Pomodoro technique as often as possible.
I have an app for my watch to start a 25-minute focus session.
And the goal is to focus for 25 minutes on a task and then take a short 5-minute break.
I always get more done when I use that technique. The break is the reward for the focus work. As far as I am concerned :) I don&amp;rsquo;t fall into the trap of distracting myself too much when I use the Pomodoro technique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>chilling in the sun</title>
      <link>/microposts/chilling-april-stay-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/microposts/chilling-april-stay-home/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limit playing games/distraction</title>
      <link>/microposts/limit-playing-games-distraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/microposts/limit-playing-games-distraction/</guid>
      <description>I got back into playing video games and especially online games but it’s a trap as well.
I already played more during the day than I usually do. Which is a bad habit. I think I need to restrict myself more. Although I used a timer to limit my daytime playing to 10-20 minutes. I just play too much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back into online gaming</title>
      <link>/microposts/back-into-online-gaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/microposts/back-into-online-gaming/</guid>
      <description>I got back into online gaming. The process was slow but got accelerated by the pandemic.
First, it was with a friend whom I used to play at his place. We just played party games with his new girlfriend.
Even before the pandemic, we wanted to play more together (because his girlfriend lives in another city). I set up everything, and then the pandemic hit, and now we played a couple of more times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Working on my environment</title>
      <link>/microposts/working-on-my-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/microposts/working-on-my-environment/</guid>
      <description>It was time to work on my environment again.
After streamlining the theme for vim across my devices (for some reason I still had solarized dark on my MacBook instead of solarized light), I decided it‘s time to look at other font options.
After researching a little bit, sitting on it for a few days, trying out a few options, I finally settled on Fira Code
It has ligatures and I must say, I did not think I would appreciate them as much as I do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profit first: Status report</title>
      <link>/microposts/profit-first-april/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/microposts/profit-first-april/</guid>
      <description>I started implementing profit first at the beginning of the year, after I listened to the Audio book.
The book got recommended by a bunch of people and I knew I wanted to get better at handling my business finances so I thought I try it out.
The book was really great and there is so much truth in the way he explains the mindset most entrepreneurs have.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t look at your balance sheet to make spending decisions you might want to try out this model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publish more</title>
      <link>/microposts/publish-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/microposts/publish-more/</guid>
      <description>I want to publish more, but I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have it go out to the void of twitter.
I found this neat idea from Justin Miller of Micro.blogs/microposts.
And I will try this out. Short thoughts or ideas that would normally go to twitter or nowhere will live here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>